{"tossups": [{"question": "Early versions of this device used rotating Nipkow disks. John Logie Baird pioneered the mechanical type of this device, which was improved upon by devices using image dissector tubes. Philo Farnsworth invented the electric version of this device, which contained cathode ray tubes that use superimposed red, green and blue to display color. For ten points, name this device whose early versions featured black and white broadcasts by NBC and CBS.", "answer": "<b> television</b> (accept<b> TV</b>)", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {}, {"question": "In this state, John Cruger fought against Nathaniel Greene and Thaddeus Kosciuszko at the Siege of 96. Alexander Stewart led a 1781 British victory along the Santee River in this state. Banastre Tarleton was defeated by a double envelopment by Daniel Morgan at this state\u2019s Battle of Cowpens. During the Revolutionary War, Charles Cornwallis inflicted a defeat on Horatio Gates at the Battle of Camden in this state. For ten points, name this state where, in 1780, American forces surrendered in the Siege of Charleston.", "answer": "<b> South Carolina</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These sites were sustained by crops harvested by \u201cneophytes.\u201d The establishment of these sites forced nearby inhabitants into lands called reductions, where they would continue to live when these sites were divided into the rancho system. Defended by royal forts called presidios, 21 of these sites were linked by El Camino Real [ree-all]. Junipero Serra supervised conversion efforts at, for ten points, what Spanish religious outposts in California?", "answer": "Spanish<b> mission</b>s in California", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This country commemorates a deadly 1952 student protest on Language Movement Day. A university in this country was attacked by tanks to flush out Chhatra League leaders in 1971. Yahya Khan launched Operation Searchlight to suppress the independence-seeking Awami League in this country, which was known at the time as East Pakistan. For ten points, name this country that, after gaining its independence from Pakistan in 1971, established its capital at Dhaka.", "answer": "<b> Bangladesh</b> (prompt on East Pakistan before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This composer wrote the score to a film about a nonexistent soldier during the reign of Paul I, as well as the music for an Eisenstein historical epic,<em> Ivan the Terrible</em>, whose Part II was suppressed by Stalin. This composer of<em> Lieutenant Kij\u00b4e</em> [kee-zhay] wrote a piece for narrator and orchestra in which the title boy\u2019s grandfather is played by a bassoon and in which a canine swallows a duck whole. For ten points, name this Soviet composer of<em> Peter and the Wolf</em>.", "answer": "Sergei<b> Prokofiev</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "One philosopher from this school claimed that human mysticism was a particularly ineffable quality; that work used the example of George Fox and the Quakers to argue that the origins of a religion did not reflect its value. The author of<em> Varieties of Religious Experience</em> belonged to this school of thought, whose namesake maxim argued that the \u201cpractical effects\u201d of your conception were critical to rational thought. Charles Sanders Peirce [\u201dpurse\u201d] and William James helped found, for ten points, what American philosophical school?", "answer": "<b> pragmatism</b> (accept word forms)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This man commanded the<em> Agamemnon</em> and, later, the<em> Captain</em> under John Jervis in the Mediterranean fleet. An injury this man suffered at the Battle of Calvi left him blind in one eye; years later, this man claimed he didn\u2019t see a signal to retreat after raising his telescope to that eye. A 169 foot tall Corinthian column in central London commemorates this man\u2019s most famous battle, in which he was killed aboard the<em> Victory</em>. For ten points, name this British admiral who won the Battle of Trafalgar.", "answer": "Horatio (Lord)<b> Nelson</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "One attempt to bankrupt this organization involved transferring its funds into the Alliance of Trade Unions, or OPZZ. After putting forth the 21 demands of the Inter-Enterprise committee, this organization argued for reforms with Wojciech Jaruzelski [voy-check yah-roo-zel-ski]. Shortly after a popular manager, Anna Walentynowicz, was fired, this organization went on strike at the Lenin Shipyard in Gdansk. Lech Walesa [lek vah-wen-sah] led, for ten points, what influential Polish labor union and political movement?", "answer": "<b> Solidarity</b> (or<b> Solidarnosc</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "John DeWitt\u2019s support of this policy including the issuing of \u201cMilitary Proclamation Number One.\u201dThis policy was implemented at sites like Heart Mountain and Topaz, as well as a site photographed by Ansel Adams and Dorothea Lange, Manzanar. Gordon Hirabayashi and Minoru Yasui both brought lawsuits against this policy. Executive Order 9066 put into effect, for ten points, what American policy of forced relocation and imprisonment of people of a certain Asian nationality during World War II?", "answer": "Japanese-American<b> internment</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This empire\u2019s last ruler, Brihadratha, was assassinated by Pushyamitra, who then founded the Shunga Dynasty. The second ruler of this empire ordered his son to capture the city of Takshashila. Megasthenes negotiated a peace agreement and marriage alliance in which this empire sent 500 elephants to the neighboring Seleucid Empire. A series of edicts in this empire were inscribed on pillars topped by lions and issued by its third ruler. For ten points, name this ancient Indian empire founded by Chandragupta and ruled by Ashoka [ah-shoke].", "answer": "<b> Mauryan</b> Empire", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The leader removed from power in this event had campaigned with the slogan \u201cEvolution in Continuity.\u201d Shortly after this event began, a suspension bridge to Almada, colored similarly to the Golden Gate Bridge, was re-named for it. The (+) beginning of this event was signaled with a Paulo de Carvalho song from the prior year\u2019s Eurovision Song Contest. Marcello (*)</b> Caetano was removed from power in this event, which ended a regime began by Antonio Salazar. The Estado Novo ended with, for ten points, what peaceful 1974 Portuguese revolution?", "answer": "<b> Carnation</b> Revolution (accept<b> 25th of April</b> Revolution)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This country was the site of the 1983 Black July pogrom, which triggered a civil war. The first female ruler of an Asian nation, Queen Anula, ruled the Anuradhapura kingdom in what is now this country. The (+) Pali Canon, an ancient Buddhist scripture, was recorded in this country after being composed in northern India. (*) </b> Kandy was the last independent kingdom in this modern country, which is connected to the mainland by Adam\u2019s Bridge. For ten points, name this island country, known as Ceylon during its British occupation, found off the coast of India.", "answer": "<b> Sri Lanka</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A portrait of this man shows him wearing a billowing red cape in a storm as two cherubs stand behind him holding onto a red string. That Benjamin West portrait of this man was</b> <b>a study for a larger painting, never completed, that was to be donated to a (+)</b> <b>hospital</b> <b>founded by him. This man created a drawing labeled with abbreviations of colonies next to the eight (*) </b> cut sections of a snake above the caption \u201cJoin or Die.\u201d For ten points, name this founding father shown in the painting \u201cDrawing Electricity out of the Sky\u201d holding a key on a kite string.", "answer": "Benjamin<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The McGovern-Fraser Commission was created to solve</b> <b>the problems that arose at one of these events that was marred by (+)</b> <b>Robert Kennedy\u2019s</b> <b>assassination three months earlier. At the 2016 version of this event, Khizr Khan, a Gold Star parent, criticized (*)</b> Donald Trump\u2019s campaign promises. For ten points, name this quadrennial event at which politicians like Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton have been nominated to run for President by their party.", "answer": "<b> Democratic National Convention</b>s (or<b> DNC</b>s) Page 9", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>During this event, Helene is killed by a rapist who bites her, though the rapist himself is killed by the apprentice of the wood carver Master Niklaus. This historical event provides</b> <b>the backdrop of Hermann Hesse\u2019s novel (+)</b> <em><b>Narcissus and Goldmund</b></em><b>. Seven women and</b> <b>three men share a hundred stories with each other while fleeing this event in (*)</b> Florence in Giovanni Boccaccio\u2019s<em> Decameron</em>. Early treatments of the Danse Macabre motif depict the ravages of, for ten points, what Medieval epidemic?", "answer": "<b> Black Death</b> (accept the black<b> plague</b>; accept the bubonic<b> plague</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "<b>During this event, a Writers Union commission headed by Jaroslav Seifert investigated crimes against literary figures. This event prompted a promise of intervention in the</b> <b>Bratislava Declaration. The Two Thousand (+)</b> <b>Words manifesto was issued during</b> <b>this period, whose end was protested by Jan Palach\u2019s [yan pal-ok\u2019s] self-immolation in Wenceslas Square. During this period, newly elected First Secretary Alexander (*)</b> Dubcek [doob-check] attempted to implement \u201cSocialism with a human face.\u201d For ten points, name this period of Czechoslovakian liberalization that was crushed by a 1968 Soviet invasion.", "answer": "<b> Prague Spring</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Vice Admiral William McRaven organized this event, which was planned for the night of the White House Correspondents Dinner. In the aftermath of this event, the perpetrators</b> <b>consulted the (+)</b> <b>Saudi Arabian government while onboard the USS</b><em><b> Carl Vinson</b></em><b> before</b> <b>Saudi Arabian government while onboard the USS</b><em><b> Carl Vinson</b></em><b> before</b> <b>burying a corpse in the North Arabian (*)</b> <b>burying a corpse in the North Arabian (*)</b> Sea. A courier named Abu Ahmed al-Kuwaiti was tracked to discover the location of this event\u2019s target, who was codenamed \u201cGeronimo.\u201d For ten points, name this May 2, 2011 event in which members of SEAL Team Six killed the leader of Al-Qaeda.", "answer": "<b> assassination</b> (or<b> killing</b>,<b> shooting</b>, etc.) of Osama<b> bin Laden</b> (accept Operation<b> Neptune Spear</b>)  (1) <b>One leader from this dynasty scored a decisive victory against the chained-up</b> <b>One leader from this dynasty scored a decisive victory against the chained-up</b> <b>ships of his rival in the Battle of Yamen. The Manichaeist (+)</b> <b>ships of his rival in the Battle of Yamen. The Manichaeist (+)</b> <b>White Lotus Society</b> <b>expanded its influence during this dynasty, eventually toppling it in the Red Lotus</b> <b>Rebellion. The most prominent emperor of this dynasty moved its capital from Xanadu</b> <b>to (*) </b> Dadu, and failed twice in trying to conquer Japan after seeing his ships annihilated by typhoons. For ten points, name this Mongol-led dynasty founded by Kublai Khan. ANSWER:<b> Yuan</b> Dynasty (accept the<b> Great Yuan</b> Dynasty)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}